<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="docbook-css/driver.css" type="text/css"?>

<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="index" xml:lang="en">
<info>
<title>Putting Cards on the Table (2019-*)</title>
<authorgroup>
<author>
<personname>
<firstname>Shlomi</firstname>
<surname>Fish</surname>
</personname>
<affiliation>
<address>
<email>shlomif@shlomifish.org</email>
<uri type="homepage" xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/">Shlomi Fish's Homepage</uri>
</address>
</affiliation>
</author>
</authorgroup>
<copyright>
<year>2019</year>
<holder>Shlomi Fish</holder>
</copyright>
<legalnotice xml:id="main_legal_notice">
<para>
<!--Creative Commons License-->
This work is licensed under the <link xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution Noncommercial (CC-by-nc) 4.0 Licence</link> (or at your option any greater version of it).
<!--/Creative Commons License-->
</para>
</legalnotice>
<revhistory>
<revision>
<revnumber>2019-11-12</revnumber>
<date>12 November 2019</date>
<authorinitials>shlomif</authorinitials>
<revremark>
First recorded and incomplete version.
</revremark>
</revision>
</revhistory>
</info>

<section xml:id="intro">

<info><title>Introduction</title></info>

<para>
This essay aims to present a summary of a snapshot as of 2022 of my personal
philosophy and ideology, titled
<link xlink:href="http://www.shlomifish.org/me/rindolf/#rindolfism">Rindolfism</link>,
which is dynamic and subject to change.
</para>

<para>
It largely builds upon a previous essay titled <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/philosophy/putting-all-cards-on-the-table-2013/">“Putting all the Cards on the Table (2013)”</link>
</para>

<para>
I am really tired of having truly intellectual people like me "speak in
riddles" and be somewhat dishonest, so I'd like to put as many of the cards I
have now on the table. There will likely be more into the future, and moreover,
honesty is a process and a person should strive to become more honest as time
goes by.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="truths-doubts-and-other-epistemology">

<info>
<title>Epistemology: Truths, "Lies", A Dynamic Reality, etc.</title>
</info>

<para>
Larry Wall <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=larry-wall-all-truth-is-gods-truh">noted:</link>
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
I have a book on my bookshelf that I’ve never read, but that has a great title.
It says, <emphasis role="bold">“All Truth is God’s Truth.”</emphasis> And I believe that. The most viable belief
systems are those that can reach out and incorporate new ideas, new memes, new
metaphors, new interfaces, new extensions, new ways of doing things. My goal
this year is to try to get Perl to reach out and cooperate with Java. I know it
may be difficult for some of you to swallow, but Java is not the enemy. Nor is
Lisp, or Python, or Tcl. That is not to say that these languages don't have
good and bad points. I am not a cultural relativist. Nor am I a linguistic
relativist. In case you hadn't noticed. :-)
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/philosophy/guide-to-neo-tech/">Neo-Tech noted something similar:</link>
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
"Truth" is a mushy, polyhydra word; everyone disputes its meaning.
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
A variant of an insight by <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Niels_Bohr">Niels Bohr</link> goes:
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
The opposite of a correct statement is a false statement. But the opposite of a
profound truth may well be another profound truth.
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
Moreover, I <link xlink:href="https://twitter.com/shlomif/status/1351069373952360448">noted in a tweet</link>:
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
Not only is "All Truth is God's Truth", but "truth" is a function of time. If
everyone copied solutions in <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Euler">Project Euler</link>
there'd be far more people who solved more than 400 problems, but people are
more honest today.
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
Moreover, note that like <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_truth_is_out_there">the X-files motto</link> goes,
<quote>The truths are out there</quote>. The media, including Internet sites,
blogs, and social media (and I may err on it too some time), will always emit
a lot of static <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/White_noise">white noise</link>
in all directions (for example see
<link xlink:href="#paris_hilton">my notes about Paris Hilton</link> later),
but people <emphasis role="bold">can</emphasis> tell the truth.
The <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hebrew_Bible">Bible</link>
depicts acts of massacre, adultery, and incest that would seem appalling,
and which historians believe were common back then (see e.g: <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Levite%27s_concubine">the story ”Levite’s concubine”</link>).
Nevertheless, generations of children (and adults) who read it, knew better
than to emulate that.
<footnote label="Definition of “media”" xml:id="media_definition">
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/media">“Media”</link> is
a plural of a “medium of communications”. Such a medium is an "in-between"
/ "in-the-middle" device or mechanism that stands between your mind, and
the observed objects.
</para>
</footnote>
</para>

<para>
Do note that there is a place for logical absolutism (= <quote>1. A is A. 2. A is not not-A. 3. Every entity is either A or not-A.</quote>; <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Term_logic">term logic</link>/etc.) -
without it mathematics won't be possible, nor will most modern engineering,
computers (including many embedded and mobile devices), and computer networking.
But I tend to agree with Bohr that often we can look at a more humane or
spiritual issue from two different valid sides.
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
“The fundamental cause of the trouble is that in the modern world the stupid are cocksure while the intelligent are full of doubt.” — <link xlink:href="https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Bertrand_Russell">Bertrand Russell</link>
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
I think that having doubts likely plays a part in making people wiser.
</para>

<para>
Like <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turn!_Turn!_Turn!">Ecclesiastes</link>
noted:
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
To every thing there is a season, and a time to every purpose under the heaven:
</para>

<para>
A time to be born, and a time to die; a time to plant, a time to reap that which is planted;
</para>

<para>
A time to kill, and a time to heal; a time to break down, and a time to build up;
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
One should apply judgement in reasoning.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="the_pygmalion_effect_and_the_golem_effect">

<info>
<title>The Pygmalion effect and the Golem effect</title>
</info>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pygmalion_effect">The Pygmalion effect</link>
notes that if one expects a person to improve, then they will often improve.
This is similar to the Greek myth of Pygmalion, who enhanced his statue until
it became alive.
</para>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golem_effect">The Golem effect</link>
notes that if one expects a person to deteriorate, then they will often deteriorate.
This is similar to the Jewish myths about the Golem.
</para>

<para>
Both are self-fulfilling prophecies.
</para>

<para>
As a result, I decided that I will expect everybody and everything to improve,
and I encourage everyone to do the same. It might or might not work, but
should not hurt.
</para>

<para>
As a case study, most cars in my neighbourhood used to not stop for letting
pedestrians cross. Then I started waving to thank those that did, like I saw
being done at Scotland. Now most of them do stop. Positive feedback often does
work.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="do_and_let_do__live_and_let_live">
<info>
<title>"Live and let live; do and let do"</title>
</info>

<para>
While it had earlier occurrences, I derive this piece of wisdom from <link
xlink:href="http://shlomifishswiki.branchable.com/Saladin_Style/">Saladin</link>,
a Muslim king and conqueror of Kurdish descent who is known for being one
of the most effective warriors, and one of the most noble and merciful people in
history.
</para>

<para>
During Saladin's time, <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palestine_(region)">Palestine</link>
which is also known as "The Land of Israel" or "The Holy Land", was ruled and
terrorised by Christian conquerors (e.g: the <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knights_Templar">Knights
Templar</link> ). These were Christian fighters who originated from Europe, who
were psychotic, psychopathological, vicious, sadistic, and vandals, who would
have put <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nazi_Germany">the
Nazis</link>, much less today's <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Al-Qaeda">Al-Qaeda</link> or <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Islamic_State_of_Iraq_and_the_Levant">ISIL</link>
to shame, and harmed the civilians in Palestine and were feared by them.
</para>

<para>
Saladin acquired a large army of loyal warriors, who all joined him by choice,
had superior swords to those of the Christians, and lighter armour, and he
set out to release Palestine from them fortress by fortress.  But the
most amazing thing is that he told the Christians something like that:
</para>

<blockquote>

<para>

You can fight me or you can surrender. The choice is yours. Do what you want,
you don't have to do what you think you must. If you choose to surrender, I
will spare your life, disarm you and let you walk to Christian-controlled
territory. If you choose to fight, I will try my best not to kill or harm you
(but do note that protecting my troops is my priority),
and then swear you not to fight me any more, and let you walk to
Christian-controlled territory.

</para>

<para>

I trust you will make the right decision and entrust you with power.
Whatever your choice will be, I'll accept it.

</para>

</blockquote>

<para>
While some crusaders were probably killed, many of them survived and became
happy, sane, and while ostensibly Christian, unwilling to fight Saladin.  Even
if their religious leaders told them to return, Saladin told them he is OK with
the oath breaking and said he'll fight them again. This caused his
opponents to fight extremely poorly, and be quickly disarmed.
Following that, they learned their lesson, and would not fight Saladin again.
</para>

<para>
By letting people do what they want, they will likely do the best thing
they can do. This is management by not managing and parenting by not
parenting, which is and always was the best way.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="big-minded-vs-small-minded">

<info>
<title>Big minded ("Rosh gadol") vs. Small minded ("Rosh qatan")</title>
</info>

<para>
The Israeli military was small, and, as there was a lot of work to do
to properly secure the Israeli civilians, it coined the terms
<link xlink:href="https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2004/12/06/news-45/">Rosh
gadol (“big minded”) and Rosh qatan (“small minded”)</link>
to encourage the soldiers to take initiative and try to perform their
jobs as well as possible, regardless of the fact they were paid little.
</para>

<para>
This extends to non-military work, government work, and voluntary work
or hobbies and endeavours: if you care about something, do it as well
as possible and give it enough time as needed. It will get easier and
faster in time.
</para>

<para>
For instance, a vendor of a candy store or an icecream parlour, should
try to greet the customers, be friendly to them, offer recommendations
to them if they ask, accept business cards with their personal web
sites or social media presence and visit them, and generally treat
every customer like royalty.
</para>

<para>
If you do this, you'll likely get more returning customers, bigger tips,
bigger bonuses and raises, and you may be able to land a better job
based on a warm recommendation from your superiors and coworkers.
</para>

<para>
The opposite is <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Micromanagement">Micromanagement</link> where you do exactly as you are told.
</para>

<para>
Note that the Nazis'
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Superior_orders">Superior
orders - "I was only following orders"</link> is orthogonal
to this. Despite common belief, the Nazis were very
<link xlink:href="https://www.geekwire.com/2011/top-10-reasons-darth-vader-amazing-project-manager/">big minded / "Rosh Gadol"</link>,
which may help explain their initial effectiveness.
</para>

<para>
One may opt to <emphasis role="bold">refuse orders</emphasis>
completely, and given the bad reputation that Superior orders got recently,
the <link xlink:href="https://www.phrases.org.uk/meanings/263700.html">"Off with
his head"</link> Shakespeare and Lewis Carroll parody of Absolutism
is unlikely to happen anywhere. If <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Catharina-Amalia,_Princess_of_Orange">the current Dutch heir apparent</link>
requests a private jet flight at nighttime for a non-Emergency
(which is what foolishly killed <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samantha_Smith">Samantha
Smith</link> and her father, and six other people),
she will probably be refused. She is unlikely to request that anyway,
but that is besides the point.
<footnote label="Why I picked the Dutch princess?" xml:id="why_nl_princess">
<para>
I picked her simply because she is older than Queen Elizabeth II's oldest
great-grandchild.
</para>
</footnote>
</para>

<para>
If your superior in any way requests something reasonable, you should comply
with their request and be bigminded about it. But feel free to refuse harmful
orders or requests. Despite common belief, this should not cause anarchy, but
rather bring peace and prosperity.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="amateurs">

<info>
<title>Amateurs vs. Professionals</title>
</info>

<para>
<link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=paul-graham-what-ameteur-meant">"Amateur"
used to mean someone who worked for the love of it</link>. Such people
often produce better results than those <link
xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bJrqpR_7VSo">who do it only
for money or even a lot of money</link>
</para>

<para>
If you care enough about a task, invest the time to do it well.
It should get quicker and easier and the results will be better and
more "professional" in due time.
</para>

<para>
In the book <link xlink:href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Three_Musketeers">The
Three Musketeers</link>, Dumas tells the story of how d’Artagnan who is a young
swordsman without much of an official training, from a remote region of France,
eventually becomes the best fighter in France. This is despite the fact that
his peers, Athos, Porthos, and Aramis, have much more experience and training.
</para>

<para>
It may seem farfetched, but before the industrialisation of the Far East,
and the way the West interpreted martial arts, with the coloured belts and
all, there were regional masters of these arts, who practised them as much as
they could and honed their skills. However, despite all that, they never ruled
out that they would one day fight against someone who never fought before,
and lose.
</para>

<para>
It took me more than a year to write <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/TheEnemy/"><emphasis>The Enemy and How I
Helped to Fight it</emphasis></link> which was my first serious story, but it took me about
two weeks to write <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/Summerschool-at-the-NSA/"><emphasis>Summerschool
at the NSA</emphasis></link>. This is whereas the screenplay for the film
<emphasis>Spaceballs</emphasis> (which was written previously by Mel Brooks, Ronny Graham, and
Thomas Meehan) took <link
xlink:href="https://thelaughbutton.com/mel-brooks/24-lesser-known-facts-spaceballs/">"only"
six months to write</link>.
</para>

<para>
Similarly, it took Bob Dylan less than 20 minutes to write <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blowin%27_in_the_Wind">"Blowin' in
the Wind"</link> which is considered a masterpiece, but he likely wrote many
lesser songs before that.
</para>

<para>
In 2022, amateurs (also known as "geeks") are often offered token pay, or
even large salaries or one-off sums of money (while agreeing to do some
commissions or jobs for free).
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="hacking-heroism">

<info>
<title>Hacking and Heroism vs. Conformism and Tragedy</title>
</info>

<para>
As you may have read, <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/philosophy/putting-all-cards-on-the-table-2013/#david_and_goliath">David
who fought Goliath was a hacker</link> and it was modernised in <link
xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=anEuw8F8cpE">the famous
scene from Indiana Jones</link> where Indy shoots a master swordsman
using a gun instead of struggling with him. Hacking or heroism involves
breaking or bending as many invisible rules as possible and not
accepting your “fate” (which is usually death) and this applies both to
fiction and to real life.
</para>

<para>
The opposite of hacking is conformism where you accept all the
normative rules of society, fear your own shadow, and stagnate and die,
possibly by <link
xlink:href="https://studybible.info/ABP_Strongs/Judges%2016:30">taking
many innocent people's lives with you</link>.
</para>

<para>
As a result, eccentricity and "craziness" are the road to a happy life,
not conformism as widely believed.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="great-hackers">

<info>
<title>Great Hackers</title>
</info>

<para>
A great hacker is an action hero that is aware enough of the essence of
hacking to become a greater and greater hacker, despite whatever
limitations he or she may have, and despite whatever setbacks they
may run into.
</para>

<para>
Note that some great hackers were clearly fictional (e.g:
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yoda">Yoda</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://www.geekwire.com/2011/top-10-reasons-darth-vader-amazing-project-manager/">Darth Vader</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milady_de_Winter">Milady de-Winter</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miss_Piggy">Miss Piggy</link>,
or <link xlink:href="https://mlp.fandom.com/wiki/Fluttershy">Fluttershy</link> ),
some were female (e.g: <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sarah_Bernhardt">Sarah Bernhardt</link>
, <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ayn_Rand">Ayn Rand</link>, and
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taylor_Swift">Taylor Swift</link>)
and some were underage (most notably <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samantha_Smith">Samantha Smith</link>, <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shirley_Temple">Shirley Temple</link>,
and <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macaulay_Culkin">Macaulay Culkin</link> ).
</para>

<para>
So don't let anything stop you.
</para>

<para>
Even our period's canonical "anti-geek", <link
xlink:href="https://bigbangtheory.fandom.com/wiki/Penny">Penny</link>
from the popular sitcom <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Big_Bang_Theory">The Big Bang Theory</link>, is a wonderful great
hacker. This is evident by her constant "hacks" (or <link
xlink:href="https://buffyfanfiction.fandom.com/wiki/Selinaverse#Dispelling_in_the_Selinaverse">"dispellings"</link>)
of the rules and prejudice of the show's more stigmatic geeks.
</para>

<footnote label="beauty-and-the-geek" xml:id="beauty_and_the_geek">
<para>
It is wrong to <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour.html#pbride_philosophers">look
down on reality show contestants</link> (and more recently - YouTubers)
who, like older forms of entertainers / philosophers, are seeking
recognition and fame. However, the show <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beauty_and_the_Geek">Beauty and the
Geek</link> was doomed
to failure because not only are most attractive girls increasingly
attracted to geeks, but they are increasingly quite geeky
themselves.
</para>

<para>
As funny as the
<link
xlink:href="http://itre.cis.upenn.edu/~myl/languagelog/archives/002892.html">"Math
is hard. Let's go shopping!"</link> meme is, you can be a geek
even if you are not too good at maths, and even shopping is a skill
that can be honed.
</para>
</footnote>

<section xml:id="fox-in-the-hens-coop">
<info>
<title>The Fox in the Chickens Coop</title>
</info>

<para>
Despite common belief what happens when you put a great hacker (whether
male or female) in a secluded place with many minor hackers or
conformists, is not one crushed great hacker, but rather many great
hackers, who spend time effort and conscious thought on satisfying
their customers, peers and superiors. That is the "fox in a chickens'
coop" motif as exemplified in <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joseph_(Genesis)">the story
of Joseph in prison in the Bible</link>, and that of <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milady_de_Winter">Milady de
Winter in "The Three Musketeers"</link>, and in the film
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don_Juan_DeMarco">"Don Juan DeMarco"</link>
. In <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/Summerschool-at-the-NSA/">my
"Summerschool at the NSA" screenplay</link>, a fictionalised <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/Summer-Glau/">Summer
Glau</link> (the actress who is notable for being featured in <link
xlink:href="https://www.explainxkcd.com/wiki/index.php/406:_Venting">xkcd: Venting</link> ) is the fox
(pardon the pun) who devours the hens of the fictionalised NSA.
</para>

<para>
I, Shlomi Fish, have done the same in real life in a top security
Israeli psychiatric ward where I was hospitalised for being non
normative, and for doing some foolish stuff. It worked surprisingly
well, and I've used the collected wisdom of Moses→Saladin→Ayn Rand→the
Beatles→Sesame Street→web 2.0 blogs and sites→My Little Pony / Taylor
Swift and my own intuition and trial and error.
</para>


<para>
It took me about 6-to-8 weeks, and I suffered from the conditions of the
hospital, but otherwise was able to hone my skills in benevolent psychological
warfare, and also started writing some essays with my limited computing
resources there.
</para>

</section>

</section>

<section xml:id="hacker-monarchs">

<info>

<title>The Hacker Monarchs / Messiahs</title>

</info>

<para>
Traditionally in history, some great hackers have been motivated enough to
change the world or improve it, and let no obstacle permanently stop them. They
have become so powerful that they took over the direction of the world and
together with some collaborators and supporters became sources of greatness.
This is even though some of them were clearly or presumably fictional.
</para>

<para>
We'll call them the "Hacker Monarchs" ("Hacker Kings" / "Hacker Queens")
which is a less loaded title than "Messiahs".
</para>

<section xml:id="hacker-monarchs-nature">

<info>
<title>The nature of The Hacker Monarchs</title>
</info>

<para>
We are still figuring out more and more guidelines for how a hacker monarch
should behave, and likely there'll be future insights.
</para>

<para>
In <link
xlink:href="https://memory-alpha.fandom.com/wiki/Grand_Nagus">the
article about the Grand Nagus in Star Trek DS9</link>, Quark is quoted
as saying:
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
Oh believe me, the Nagus has the greatest business mind in
the entire Ferengi Alliance, always thinking ten, sometimes twenty
steps ahead of everyone else.
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
and this is similar for a hacker monarch
who is often ahead of the curve. A messiah also attempts to always think
a few steps ahead.
</para>

<para>
A hacker monarch believes that the correct answer to the question "Who is the
most powerful person on Earth?" is "I am". Furthermore, the only less powerful
people are those who answer otherwise.
</para>

<para>
They also know they can improve themselves, improve the world at large,
and enjoy themselves — all at the same time.
</para>

<para>
In addition, a hacker monarch wishes no man or woman to unnecessarily suffer
or die prematurely and from unnatural causes. They also want
<link xlink:href="#the_pygmalion_effect_and_the_golem_effect">every
person and collective
to improve and become better</link> (= the Pygmalion effect as
opposed to <link xlink:href="#the_pygmalion_effect_and_the_golem_effect">the Golem effect</link>).
</para>

<para>
A hacker monarch <emphasis role="bold">is</emphasis> <quote>their brothers’ keeper</quote>
to paraphrase on <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cain_and_Abel">the Cain and Abel myth</link>.
For example <link xlink:href="#Christina_Grimmie">Christina Grimmie</link>
has tried to adapt herself and her work to what she thought others wanted
for several years before her assassination at age 22 (by a fan who killed
himself later almost immediately). While it was ultimately her fault,
she had many fans and viewers and friends who could have noticed (including
I).
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="notable-hacker-monarchs">

<info>
<title>Some notable hacker monarchs</title>
</info>

<para>
Some examples for notable Hacker Monarchs, from my Jewish/Secular
Israeli and Western (Near East/Europe/North Americas) bias, are:
</para>

<orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moses">Moses</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyrus_the_Great">Cyrus the Great</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Socrates">Socrates</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plato">Plato</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aristotle">Aristotle</link> (believed to have been a band of philosophers with a central poster boy figure)
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/So-Who-The-Hell-Is-Qoheleth/">Qoheleth / Ecclesiastes</link>
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
( <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesus">Jesus</link> may
have been a hacker monarch, but I have not studied his teachings closely,
and I have some natural aversion towards Christianity as an Israeli Jew. )
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muhammad">Muhammad</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="http://shlomifishswiki.branchable.com/Saladin_Style/">Saladin</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leonardo_da_Vinci">Leonardo da Vinci</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galileo_Galilei">Galileo Galilei</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isaac_Newton">Isaac Newton</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cardinal_Richelieu">Cardinal Richelieu</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Revolution">The American Revolutionaries</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexandre_Dumas">Alexandre Dumas</link> (pere)
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jules_Verne">Jules Verne</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walt_Disney">Walt Disney</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ayn_Rand">Ayn Rand</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles">The Beatles</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sesame_Street">Sesame Street</link> /
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jim_Henson">Jim Henson</link> /
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Muppets">The Muppets</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samantha_Smith">Samantha Smith</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Stallman">Richard Stallman</link> /
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/Larry-Wall/">Larry Wall</link> /
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linus_Torvalds">Linus Torvalds</link>
and other Usenet / FOSS hackers with
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eric_S._Raymond">Eric S. Raymond</link> writing the Magnus Opus <link xlink:href="http://www.catb.org/~esr/writings/cathedral-bazaar/">CatB</link>.
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
The fictional <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean-Luc_Picard">Jean-Luc Picard</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
The fictional <link xlink:href="https://buffy.fandom.com/wiki/Buffy_Summers">Buffy Summers</link> being the poster girl of "Web 1.0".
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joel_Spolsky">Joel Spolsky</link> /
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eric_S._Raymond">Eric S. Raymond</link> /
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Graham_(programmer)">Paul Graham (programmer)</link> /
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lawrence_Lessig">Lawrence Lessig</link> / <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/">Shlomi Fish</link>
 and other software developers and bloggers / web writers of the
~2000-2014 web 2.0/"open content" revolution.
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
In <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/Summerschool-at-the-NSA/">Summerschool at the NSA</link>, I believed
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/Summer-Glau/">Summer Glau</link>
and <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xkcd">Xkcd</link>
will succeed me. While other "messiahs" / hacker-monarchs in the past tried
to convince everyone else to consider themselves as such, it was only
possible after the web became prevalent.
</para>
</listitem>

</orderedlist>

<para>
Following the <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/me/rindolf/#update_long_live_us_hacker_monarchs">Summer
Glau "termination"</link>, it was believed that there now can be many
simultaneous hacker monarchs, and that people can try to become ones while not
dethroning (or <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sic_transit_gloria_mundi">sic transit
gloria mundi</link>) the previous hacker monarchs. <quote>We don’t die. We multiply.</quote>
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="hacker-monarchs-fallability">

<info>
<title>Hacker Monarchs being Fallible</title>
</info>

<para>
Note that even a hacker monarch may be fallible. Socrates almost got himself
killed several times, and then he willingly drank the poison and died.
Plato and Aristotle said equally blasphemous things, but learned from Socrates'
fate and worked on better delivery so both died as highly revered and
respected. The same story repeated itself during the Renaissance with Galileo
and Isaac Newton.
</para>

<para>
Many Hacker Monarchs were two steps forward and one step back, like the fact
Ayn Rand was <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/culture/case-for-commercial-fan-fiction/#open_free_share_steal">anti-Open</link> and
<link xlink:href="#amateurs">anti-Amateur</link> and <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=neo-tech-selfishness">confused
selfishness with rational self growth</link>.
</para>

<para>
Moreover, I still resent the fact that the characters in
<emphasis>Buffy</emphasis> were competent, but on the other hand socially inept
and lacked sexual assertiveness. This is a false dichotomy that I tried to
rectify in <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/stories/">my
stories and screenplays</link> where the characters are both competent and
socially capable.
</para>

<para>
Having read <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Three_Musketeers"><emphasis>The
Three Musketeers</emphasis></link>, Dumas’ magnus opus, I recall feeling
intimated by the competence and resourcefulness of <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milady_de_Winter">Milady de
Winter</link>, until I eventually realised that despite being the antagonist,
or because of that, she was the ultimate good in the book, and she became my
epitome of sexiness in fiction. I disliked the fact that Dumas killed her so much, that
I set out to carve different destinies for her in <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/Selina-Mandrake/"><emphasis>Selina
Mandrake - The Slayer</emphasis></link> and for <link
xlink:href="https://buffy.fandom.com/wiki/Faith_Lehane">Faith</link> (her rough
equivalent in <emphasis>Buffy the Vampire Slayer</emphasis>) in <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/Buffy/A-Few-Good-Slayers/"><emphasis>Buffy
- a Few Good Slayers</emphasis></link>.
</para>

<para>
So if you have a criticism against even the greatest hackers, voice it - we
<link
xlink:href="http://shlomifishswiki.branchable.com/Encourage_criticism_and_try_to_get_offended/">can
only benefit from it</link>.  Also see <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Emperor%27s_New_Clothes">The
Emperor's New Clothes</link> .
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="other-names-for-hacker-monarchs">

<info>
<title>Other names for Hacker Monarchs</title>
</info>

<orderedlist>

<listitem>
<para>
Hacker Kings / Hacker Queens ("Hacker Queen Regnent").
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
Messiahs.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://memory-alpha.fandom.com/wiki/Kahless_the_Unforgettable">Warrior King</link> / Warrior Queen / Warrior Queen Regnent / Warrior Monarch
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/King_of_Kings">King of Kings</link>
</para>

<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="http://shlomifishswiki.branchable.com/Fluttershy__44___Princess_of_Princesses__44___head_of_the_secret_cabal_leadership_of_the_Mossad__44___the_already_top_secret_intelligence_agency_of_the_Zionist_conspiracy/">"Princess of Princesses"</link>
</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UHZuLMFfriQ">Best of the Best of the Best</link>
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
In <link xlink:href="https://buffyfanfiction.fandom.com/wiki/Selinaverse">the Selinaverse</link> they
are referred to as "Q"s or later as "Sith"s.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=sharp-gamedev--make-everyone--messiahs">A "Pope"</link> by Principia Discordia.
</para>
</listitem>

</orderedlist>

</section>

</section>

<section xml:id="make-your-own-kind-of-music">

<info>
<title>Make your own kind of music / Take your qualities to your advantage</title>
</info>

<para>
Similar to the <link
xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SbSM02_1k34">Mama Cass Elliot song
"make your own kind of music"</link> or its Lady Gaga
modernisation <link
xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xG0wi1m-89o">"Born This Way"</link>, I have given an interpretation of <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/Buffy/A-Few-Good-Slayers/ongoing-text.html#faith-s-childhood">Captain
Nemo</link> (= "nobody" in Latin)
<footnote label="Finding Nemo" xml:id="finding_nemo">
<para>
And not to be confused with Nemo from the animated film <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finding_Nemo">Finding Nemo</link>.
</para>
</footnote>
in Jules Verne's novel <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twenty_Thousand_Leagues_Under_the_Sea">20,000
Leagues Under the Sea</link>, whom people keep finding interesting for what he
believes are superficial reasons. But these qualities are part of what makes us
who we are.
</para>

<para xml:id="Cimorelli-ren">
The YouTuber band <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cimorelli">Cimorelli</link> has used
the fact that they are six sisters (who also have five male brothers) in a large
Roman Catholic family, a trend which has received a lot of antagonism, from
environmentalists, psychologists and the media, to their advantage, and as a
gimmick. As a result, they published many videos of them covering hit songs,
some original songs, and have been live performing and collaborating with other
singers and entertainers.
</para>

<para>
Naturally, they are not the only YouTube success story. But if you get an
opportunity, seize it. Were you invited to give a talk? Go for it. Even if you
were invited from the "wrong" reason, you will pave the road for future
lecturers. A sociology student invited you to talk to them about your work as
an open source / open content creator? Go for it. You thought of a new <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/">Chuck Norris/etc.
factoid</link>? Write it down and share it on social media and chat. Someone
asked you out and you like them and are single? Go for it. You have an idea for
a nice video, story, screenplay, song, etc. Execute it.
</para>

<para>
I used to be jealous of <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ayn_Rand">Ayn Rand</link>
for writing so lucidly and coherently in <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Fountainhead"><emphasis>The Fountainhead</emphasis></link>
and in <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atlas_Shrugged"><emphasis>Atlas Shrugged</emphasis></link>, whereas my style
of screenplays and stories was what I described as <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Staccato">"staccato"</link> where I do not
mention any unnecessary details. However, Rand likely felt the
same way about <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fyodor_Dostoevsky">Dostoevsky</link>
and <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_Tolstoy">Tolstoy</link>,
whose overly verbose style is now the terror and hatred of many Literature students.
</para>

<para>
Similarly, current and future generations will likely appreciate my staccato
style more than Ayn Rand’s. Make your own kind of music!
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="time-is-much-more-important-than-money">
<info>
<title> Time &gt;&gt; Money</title>
</info>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://twitter.com/shlomif/status/1175578541292957696">This tweet reads:</link>
<blockquote>
<para>
If you meet <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taylor_Swift">Taylor Swift</link> on the street, have a pleasant conversation with her,
and you need some money and ask her for some, she'll
tell you: “Sure! I don't use <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bitcoin">Bitcoin</link> because I
value my time, energy and happiness too much - and those
of the world's!
But I've got $1,000 and $100 bills, and have
a credit card if you need less. I can use <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PayPal">PayPal</link> on
my smartphone, or
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Society_for_Worldwide_Interbank_Financial_Telecommunication">SWIFT</link>.”
</para>
<para>
“So…” she'll add, “…how much money do you want?”
</para>
<para>
“How much is too much?”
</para>
<para>
"Oh, try me."
</para>
</blockquote>
</para>

<para>
There are likely many <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonprofit_organization">Nonprofit
organizations</link> with millions of dollars in the bank and not enough
skilled volunteers' time to do anything with them.
</para>

<para>
If we take <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sarah_Michelle_Gellar">Sarah
Michelle Gellar (SMG)</link> for example, she went from donating money,
back when she played <link
xlink:href="https://buffy.fandom.com/wiki/Buffy_Summers">Buffy</link> into
dedicating time for worthwhile causes after that:
</para>

<para>

<blockquote>
<para>
I started because my mother taught me a long time ago that even when you have
nothing, there's ways to give back. And what you get in return for that is
tenfold. But it was always hard because I couldn't do a lot. I couldn't do much
more than just donate money when I was on [Buffy] because there wasn't time.
And now that I have the time, it's amazing.
</para>
</blockquote>

</para>

<para>
Like the old Beatles' song goes <link xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=srwxJUXPHvE"> <quote>I don't care too much for money. Money can't buy me love.</quote></link>.
</para>

<mediaobject>
<videoobject>
<videodata>https://www.youtube.com/embed/srwxJUXPHvE</videodata>
</videoobject>
</mediaobject>

</section>

<section xml:id="karma">

<info>
<title>Karma, "What goes around, comes around"</title>
</info>

<para>
From my experience,
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karma#Comparable_concepts">Karma</link> and "What goes around, comes around" are real.
It is also evident that Ayn Rand incorporated her belief of them in <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Fountainhead"><emphasis>The Fountainhead</emphasis></link>.
Apathy and cruelty (as well as carelessness, paranoia, hubris, etc.)
tend to retaliate, while being noble and generous pays back in spades.
</para>

<para>
I decided that if someone asks me for me money, I will give them up to
a reasonable amount (e.g: <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/Summerschool-at-the-NSA/#the-resentful-beggar">the resentful beggar case</link>,
or
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/true-stories/my-first-kiss/">the story of my first kiss</link> ).
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="one-tin-soldier">

<info>
<title>&quot;One Tin Soldier&quot; and the senselessness of destruction</title>
</info>

<para>
I discovered the song <link
xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cTBx-hHf4BE">"One Tin
Soldier"</link> - an anti war song from 1969, by accident through <link
xlink:href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/pachelbel-rant">Rob Paravonian's
Pachelbel Rant</link>. I found it saddening and touching.
</para>

<para>
While I like the song as is, I wish for <link
xlink:href="#Cimorelli-ren">Cimorelli</link> who are known for their upbeat
and energetic music to cover it. But like <link
xlink:href="http://shlomifishswiki.branchable.com/Self-Sufficiency/">Hillel
the Elder noted:</link> <quote>If I am not for myself, who will be?</quote>
so I plan to record it myself using my poor man's tools, while emulating
Cimorelli's style: <link xlink:href="https://ffmpeg.org">ffmpeg</link>, my
web cam, and <link
xlink:href="https://www.audacityteam.org">audacity</link> all running on a
<link xlink:href="https://duckduckgo.com/desktop_Linux?ia=web">desktop
Linux</link> system.
</para>

<para>
The song indicates that any destruction of lives, costly equipment
or buildings, or even anti-spam measures, and removal/censorship
of web or social media resources is self-defeating and wrong.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="meaning-of-able-competent">

<info>
<title>What do "able" and "competent" imply?</title>
</info>

<para>
Karl Marx famously <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/From_each_according_to_his_ability,_to_each_according_to_his_needs">remarked</link>
<blockquote>
<para>
From each according to his ability, to each according to his needs
</para>
</blockquote>
</para>
<para>
However, this is wrong because we should encourage people to be
more able and more competent, and be less needy. So assuming we
wish people to be more able, how do we measure it?
</para>
<orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>
The first measure of ability is <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Money">Money</link> - the more
money you have the more goods you can
afford, the more you can give, donate, lend, or
invest,
and the more free time you have to do creative works.
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
The second measure of ability is <link
xlink:href="https://twitter.com/shlomif/status/1175430272130650112">Fame</link>,
the more people heard about
you the more places will invite you to be present and even pay you
for your time.
</para>

<para>
Fame has got a bad reputation lately, but I believe it is undeserved.
Even if you are famous, you do not necessarily have to suffer from it.
</para>

</listitem>

<listitem>

<para xml:id="paris_hilton">
The third measure is "luck" which is which opportunities you seize. The
media went out of its way to present <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paris_Hilton">Paris
Hilton</link>, who was the canonical "alpha female" in the world throughout
several years between 2000 and 2014, as incompetent, talentless, stupid, and
lucky to have been a heiress by birth. However, despite that, she was the
opposite of most of these. Moreover, if she utilised her initial state to
her own advantage, then all the power to her.
</para>

<para>
Earlier in 1982, <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samantha_Smith">Samantha Smith</link>
may have been lucky for her letter to have arrived to the Soviet leader, but
she hoped for that and planned that. It is likely that her friends found her a
little "weird" for her habit of sending letters, given my friends looked down
on a similar habit I had in the early 1990s before the prevalence of
the Internet.
</para>

</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
In today's Internet's social media, one can get a cheaper indication of some of
these, using views, upvotes, likes, "karma", reposts, replies, etc.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
Naturally, abilities can refer to your various artistic, craftsmanship,
sports, social, and intellectual skills.
</para>
</listitem>

</orderedlist>

<section xml:id="sexiness-as-competence">

<info>
<title>Sexiness as Competence</title>
</info>

<para>
Now here is something interesting: there is a strong correlation between
how able you are and how sexually desirable you are to
members-of-the-appropriate-sexes (MOTAS) (who may still be attracted to you
whether or not you or they are in a relationship.).
</para>

<para>
Furthermore, <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fitness_(biology)">fitness in
biology</link> in humans corresponds more to sexual attractiveness than to
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physical_fitness">physical
fitness</link>. In the United Kingdom, the adjective "fit" has started to mean
"sexy", "hot", "attractive" or "desirable" including to describe such
MOTAS who are not too athletic.
</para>

<para>
Some people may still think that sexual attractiveness is indicative of
incompetence and bad form, but the opposite is true. Back when I referred a
deaf friend of mine to the video <link
xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=21uXcvD5lPs">Daily Gradvice</link>
(tongue-in-cheek sex/love/etc. advice by <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grace_Helbig">Grace Helbig</link>) he
complained that the quality of the subtitles there (which were generated by
automatic <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_recognition">Speech
recognition</link>) was like "her butt before she cleans it up". I took offence
for that because I knew she was a wonderful lady and that was <emphasis
role="bold">because</emphasis> she was so sexy and sexualised, not despite
that.
</para>

<footnote label="conclusion" xml:id="daily_gradvice_conclusion">
<para>
The end of the story is that I told my friend that I would try to prepare
better subtitles which he and others would be able to use. While his original
insulting delayed that, I eventually yielded <link
xlink:href="https://github.com/shlomif/subtitles-for-dailygrace-on-youtube">functional
subtitles</link> for the video, which my deaf friend was able to use (and
can be used by everyone else who wishes to use them).
</para>
</footnote>
</section>

</section>

<section xml:id="Taylor_Swift">

<info>
<title>Taylor Swift</title>
</info>

<para>
We were <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=sharp-gnu--think-big">discussing</link>
Apple's <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swift_(programming_language)">Swift
language</link> the other day on the <link
xlink:href="irc://irc.freenode.net/#gnu">#gnu</link> chat room on freenode
when I told someone there that he should charge 300 USD/hour for Swift
projects because he disliked them so much. I also said the high fee may
yield <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=joel-camels-rubber-duckies-11">a
higher demand</link>.  Then, since I had a browser window open with the most
followed
Twitter accounts and <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taylor_Swift">Taylor Swift</link>
was there, I noted she likely charges more than 300 USD/hour for her
live shows. He told me that she shared her name with that language, and I
noted that she should sue Apple for trademark violations of the supposed
"Swift" trademark - and win.  I joked that if "Apple sued Taylor Swift for
violation of their Apple Swift language's trademark they will spend all
their money on litigation and still lose.". Ha ha only serious.
</para>

<para>
I then realised that Ms. Swift has become a <link
xlink:href="#hacker-monarchs">Hacker Queen</link> by that time. While I
think her face is good eye candy, she is not that beautiful in my opinion
(but I think she looks <link
xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IdneKLhsWOQ">much hotter with
black hair</link> than with her trademark blonde hair). Nevertheless, there
are many things we can learn from her.
</para>

<para>
First of all is that she exemplifies the <link
xlink:href="#amateurs">amateur model</link>, because she does stuff for
fun, rather than for money.
</para>

<para>
Her videos despite often being popular probably do not offset their
production value in ads, but they are good publicity, provide fodder
for remixes, parodies and covers, and are fun enough to produce so she
can afford to offset the cost. She doesn't work for money or even for a
shitload of money. She works for fun.
</para>

<para>
Moreover, Taylor is an unapologetic <link
xlink:href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/attention_whore">"attention
whore"</link> who often spends large amounts of money or even also time
on activities that will make her look like a better person or more
well known. Note that per <link xlink:href="https://www.chabad.org/library/bible_cdo/aid/16006/jewish/Chapter-9.htm">Jeremiah chapter 9 22-23:</link>
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
Thus says the Lord: Let not the wise man boast of his wisdom, nor the strong man boast of his strength, nor the rich man boast of his riches.
But he who understands and knows me, let him boast of that, for I am the Lord.
</para>

<para>
Who practices kindness, justice and righteousness on the earth; for in these things I delight, says the Lord.
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
I not only hold it against her, but encourage other do-gooders to
do the same. Furthermore, to paraphrase a quote from
<link xlink:href="https://m.imdb.com/title/tt0106941/">the film "For Love or Money"</link>
she doesn't do it because she seeks attention - she does it because
she cares.
</para>

<para>
Otherwise, Taylor Swift is a great philanthropist who likely <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=shlomif-fact-taylor-swift-6">also
donates to friendly individuals</link> and realises that one should <link
xlink:href="https://biblehub.com/ecclesiastes/11-1.htm">"cast your bread
upon the waters"</link> to quote the wonderful Biblical scroll of <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ecclesiastes">Ecclesiastes</link>.
</para>

<para>
One advice I can give to Ms. Swift is to stop "speaking in riddles" which was
also an issue of <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terry_Pratchett">Terry Pratchett’s
books</link> and previously Ayn Rand's. I registered that idiom from the lyrics
of <link xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QNzj55CEoMI">a cover of
Swift's song "Ours"</link> (which I now much malign). I recommend she start
writing a public snapshot of her personal philosophy ("Taytayism" or whatever)
similar to my <link
xlink:href="https://github.com/shlomif/putting-cards-2019-2020">repository of
this very document</link>.  It can be on GitHub or GitLab, or perhaps Google
Docs.
</para>

<para>
Another piece of advice is to
<link xlink:href="#emulate-YouTubers">emulate YouTubers</link> and start
an "indie" YouTube channel, but this is not particularly specific to her.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="Chuck_Norris">

<info>
<title>Chuck Norris</title>
</info>

<para>
My <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/philosophy/putting-all-cards-on-the-table-2013/#chuck_norris">previous
analysis of Chuck Norris and the Chuck Norris factoids trend</link> turned out
to not be the last word on the subject. It is well known that Norris took the
facts to his advantage, and as a result became the most prominent actor in
Hollywood (which I call "the Alpha Male"). However, shortly afterwards, the
factoids seem to have fallen out of favour, and some time after that, Norris
announced that he retired from acting.
</para>

<para>
Now, I still added factoids about other subjects <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/">to
my collection</link>. Then one day in 2019, I was chatting on the #gnu chat
room on <link xlink:href="https://freenode.net/">freenode</link> and after
giving someone some advice, I came up with a new factoid which I uttered
there: <quote>If Chuck Norris gives you some advice, and you do not follow
it, he'll survive. However, you likely won't.</quote>. To my surprise,
my fellow to the conversation, told me it was funny.  Some days later I
spent some time with my sister's husband, who is an artist and a film
maker, and showed him some of the software applications and web services, which
I was familiar with as a <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux">Linux (or rather
    "GNU/Linux")</link> user and developer. Then, just when he and my sister were going
away, I told him I had some factoids on my site about Chuck Norris/etc., and he
told me he was a big fan of those.
</para>

<para>
So what has happened?
</para>

<para>
What I think happened is that Norris started playing (and fighting) in
roles he liked, even if he didn't get paid or got paid relatively little,
or was paid after the fact.  He became a happy <link
xlink:href="#amateurs">amateur</link>, rather than an increasingly unhappy
professional. I won't be surprised if he has agreed to appear at local
schools' plays, and/or playing roles that were seemingly unlike his
traditional Hollywood roles - just because he liked them.
</para>

<para>
As a result of that, I believe Chuck Norris, both himself and
the fictionalised Chuck Norris Facts image, has become a
new <link xlink:href="#hacker-monarchs">Hacker Monarch</link>. Well Done!
</para>

<section xml:id="factoids_trend">

<info>
<title>Update about the factoids’ trend</title>
</info>

<para>
To my knowledge, I was the first to have come up with factoids
about a fictional female (= <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/Xena/">Xena
the Warrior Princess</link>). Later on,
inspired by <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=summer-glau-vs-chuck-norris">an IRC
chat</link>, I came up with <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/Summer-Glau/">factoids</link>
about a real life female, Summer Glau. These were followed by some factoids about
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/Emma-Watson/">Emma Watson</link>,
and more recently some about <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/Taylor-Swift/">Taylor Swift</link>.
</para>

<para>
My friends and I also came up with factoids about inanimate technologies and organisations
such as <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/Windows-Update/">those about Windows Update</link>.
</para>

</section>

</section>

<section xml:id="fear-is-path-to-dark-side">

<info>
<title>"Fear is the path to the dark side"</title>
</info>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://starwars.fandom.com/wiki/Yoda">Master Yoda</link>
from Star Wars
is a <link xlink:href="#great-hackers">great
hacker</link>, despite being fictional, and we can learn a lot from what
<link xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kFnFr-DOPf8">he said
about being unnecessarily paranoid:</link>
</para>

<blockquote>

<para>
Fear is the path to the dark side. Fear leads to anger, anger leads to hate,
hate leads to suffering. And I sense much fear in you.
</para>

</blockquote>

<para>
When one is irrationally paranoid, he will become suspicious, distrustful,
and overzealous, and demonise people who care about him, and cause him
to lose property (including data) or even his life.
As I <link xlink:href="https://twitter.com/shlomif/status/1324813236114497538">noted in a tweet</link>:
</para>

<blockquote>

<blockquote>

<para>
I'm a full professor at an ancient university and I got here through hard work, high intelligence (lots of very clever people think I'm very clever), persistence, pulling my weight and…
</para>

<para>
AMAZING AMOUNTS OF LUCK
</para>

</blockquote>

<para>
I recall that in the <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kung_Fu_Panda_(film)">first Kung Fu Panda</link> film,
<link xlink:href="https://kungfupanda.fandom.com/wiki/Oogway">master
Oogway</link> noted that <quote>There are no accidents</quote>.
Not saying it's always the case, but many incidents happen to you
because you wanted them or was prepared for them. Maybe luck has less to do
with pure chance than we assume.
</para>

</blockquote>

<para>
Thinking you have bad luck and being pessimstic may be self-fulfilling.
</para>

<para>
Following the <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Snowden">Snowden
findings</link>, some people decided to go to great lengths to avoid the NSA,
CIA, or FBI, knowing about their private lives, and online services such as
Google or Facebook "fingerprinting" them.
</para>

<para>
However, do you honestly think the NSA/etc. hate you enough to harm you?
In my <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/SummerNSA/">#SummerNSA effort</link>,
 I have said many unkind things about <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/NSA/">an idolised
version of the NSA</link>, and nothing happened to me, my homesite, and my
other online writings / blogging. (And I announced <link
xlink:href="https://www.reddit.com/r/xkcd/comments/1bignr/xkcdinspired_screenplay_starring_summer_glau_as/">the
“Summerschool at the NSA” screenplay</link> on Reddit several months
before the Snowden findings of fact.)
</para>

<para>
Moreover, I had much earlier written and published
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/TheEnemy/">“The Enemy and How I Helped to Fight it”</link>,
which is a surrealistic political satire that
criticised <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hezbollah">the Hizbullah</link>
at the time, but which I can also retrospectively tell had a lot of criticism directed
at the <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Israel_Defense_Forces">Israeli military (= IDF)</link>,
Israel, and other organisations. Since my home address is
common knowledge, Iran could have killed me a long time ago.
</para>

<para>
On the Freenode online chat service, a chat friend told us that <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=sharp-programming-nomable-browsers">he
was glad that Google has his gmail.com E-mail messages</link> because it means
someone else besides him has them, and so they are less likely to get lost like
his previous E-mail messages got lost in a hard disk failure.
</para>

<para>
I keep most of my important digital data in public repositories on <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GitHub">GitHub</link> and other “code
sharing” sites because to quote <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linus_Torvalds">Linus
Torvalds</link>: <quote>Only wimps use tape backup. Real men just upload their
important stuff on FTP and let the rest of the world mirror it.</quote>. Nowadays, one
should <link
xlink:href="https://better-scm.shlomifish.org/docs/this-site-is-irrelevant/">use
git as a version control system</link> most of the time, but the point is that
one should <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/philosophy/putting-all-cards-on-the-table-2013/#publish_or_perish">publish
or perish</link>.
</para>

<para>
(Note that there are also <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Drive">Google Drive</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_365">Microsoft 365</link>, and
similar services, which are more friendly to
laymen, have web interfaces, and have coarser-grained revision histories.)
</para>

<para>
My <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/me/contact-me/">contact
info</link> is publicly available, and I actually wish for more people -
of any sex/gender, ethnicity, talents and interests, race, nationality, etc.
- to contact me and chat in any plausible medium.
</para>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://twitter.com/sawaba/status/1038078106404315136">This
tweet reads</link>:
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
I know many people that have lost priceless data forever because they decided
that it needed the utmost protection. Family photos, months and years of coding
work, a novel… all gone, because it *had* to be encrypted.
</para>
</blockquote>

<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/security.png" />
</imageobject>
<textobject>
<phrase>xkcd 538</phrase>
</textobject>
<caption>
<para>xkcd 538</para>
</caption>
</mediaobject>

<blockquote>

<para>
<emphasis role="bold">A Crypto nerd's imagination:</emphasis>
</para>
<para>
Cueball: His laptop's encrypted. Let's build a million-dollar cluster to crack
it.
</para>
<para>
Friend: No good! It's 4096-bit RSA!
</para>
<para>
Cueball: Blast! Our evil plan is foiled!
</para>

<para>
<emphasis role="bold">What would actually happen:</emphasis>
</para>
<para>
Cueball: His laptop's encrypted. Drug him and hit him with this $5 wrench until
he tells us the password.
</para>
<para>
Friend : Got it.
</para>

<para>
<emphasis role="bold">Hover text:</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
Actual actual reality: nobody cares about his secrets. (Also, I would be
hard-pressed to find that wrench for $5.)
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
Moreover as <link
xlink:href="https://explainxkcd.com/wiki/index.php/538:_Security">xkcd
#538</link> notes, the bottleneck for revealing secrets is you and the amount
of pain and intimidation you're willing to endure. When I was a teenager, a
friend who was physically stronger, forced me to reveal the 4 digit password to
my digital watch's secret phone numbers’ storage - not unlike that xkcd strip
and   the <link
xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=94LL8J8WYT0">
“give us the gate key” scene from the film <emphasis>The Princess Bride</emphasis></link>. Moreover, as
the xkcd’s hover text notes, if
your data is worthwhile, then you’ll <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/culture/case-for-commercial-fan-fiction/indiv-nodes/open_free_share_steal.xhtml">share
it far and wide</link>.
</para>

<mediaobject>
<videoobject>
<videodata>https://www.youtube.com/embed/94LL8J8WYT0</videodata>
</videoobject>
</mediaobject>

<para>
On Facebook, a friend wrote that he wishes it did a better job at fingerprinting
him, given he was often annoyed by its recommendations.
</para>

<para>
I actually even hope my thoughts have been recorded and I wish to share them.
I have had many good ideas for hacks, memes, or fictional universes, and I'm
not ashamed of my wrong, stupid, and/or "dirty" thoughts.
I recently publicly came out with <link xlink:href="https://twitter.com/shlomif/status/1497091124984528897">my deepest secret</link>
which is (brace yourself) the fact that I'm attracted to
physically strong and/or muscular women.
And… turns out I am in good company, and I felt relieved.
</para>

<para>
My assumption is that the universe's defence community records and publishes
every important piece of information, and yet everyone and everything practise <link xlink:href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/wheatons-law">Wheaton's Law (= “Don't be a dick.”)</link>
so there's rarely a lot of damage.
Moreover, people who have malevolent, destructive, intentions, will likely be
too incompetent, careless, and sloppy, to succeed in being harmful.
Some Internet "criminals" may extract some money from the bank accounts
of profitable organisations (e.g.
from that of <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/culture/case-for-commercial-fan-fiction/indiv-nodes/money_cant_buy_you_love.xhtml">apple.com which has more than 100 milliard dollars</link>),
but they won't dare to bankrupt any of them, much less to permanently delete
a blogger's canon of gratisly-available content-and-code, that took
a lifetime to prepare.
</para>

<para>
My interest in <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_security">computer security</link>
is primarily motivated by my desire to have more reliable software,
rather than to try to protect my “privacy”.
</para>

<para>
So please do not be paranoid and overly possessive of your crown jewels.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="hakuna-matata">

<info>
<title>“Hakuna Matata” - no worries and no problems</title>
</info>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hakuna_matata">“Hakuna
matata”</link> is a phrase in some Swahili dialects, which after it was introduced in <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hakuna_Matata_(song)">a
song</link> in the Disney film <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lion_King"><emphasis>The Lion
King</emphasis></link> came to mean both "no worries" and "no problem".
</para>

<para>
Some people came up with <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/computers/open-source/foss-licences-wars/rev2/#strong-copyleft-and-threats-to-foss">elaborate
hypothetical scenarios</link> where using the more restrictive <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNU_General_Public_License">GPL
licence</link> will be advantageous instead of the <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Permissive_software_license">permissive
software licences</link> which I prefer to use for most of the <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/open-source/projects/">software</link>
which I originated. However, I was non-plussed by them and said I will be
“OK with it”. People did not violate my trust, because I entrusted them
with the power to do so, which made them feel empowered.
</para>

<para>
I believe that if the great <link
xlink:href="http://shlomifishswiki.branchable.com/Saladin_Style/">Saladin</link>
was alive today and was a developer of open source software (which <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/image-macros/indiv-nodes/if_ayn_rand_was_born_in_the_1990s.xhtml">is
not as farfetched as it sounds</link>), then he too would prefer using
permissive licences when he could help it.
</para>

<para>
I met <link xlink:href="https://blog.wikimedia.org/2019/06/22/wilfredo-rodriguez/">Wilfredo Rodriguez</link> on freenode, and he notes that he
uses the public domain ( <link xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/share-your-work/public-domain/cc0/">CC0</link> )
for most of his photos, so people can use them even without being legally
required to credit him (much less to pay him). Nevertheless, many of them
do exactly that.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="benevolent-psychological-warfare">

<info>
<title>Benevolent Psychological Warfare</title>
</info>

<para>
Benevolent psychological warfare was practised by Saladin, but was enhanced
by greater and greater action heroes / hackers throughout the ages: including
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sesame_Street">Sesame Street</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles">The Beatles</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_2.0">web 2.0 bloggers / online
writers and online entertainers</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Little_Pony:_Friendship_is_Magic">My Little Pony: Friendship is Magic</link>,
and <link xlink:href="#YouTube">YouTube videos</link>.
</para>

<para>
The good news is that it is easy to practice, and can even be applied by people
who are not in a position of power. And it can be summarised by the famous
adages
<link xlink:href="https://mygeekwisdom.com/2011/09/12/be-excellent-to-each-other/">"Be excellent to each other"</link>
and <link xlink:href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/wheatons-law">"Don't be a dick." (= Wheaton's Law)</link>.
</para>

<para>
If you interact with a fellow person, shake his hand. Expect
<link xlink:href="#the_pygmalion_effect_and_the_golem_effect">everyone
to improve and become better</link> (= the Pygmalion effect as
opposed to <link xlink:href="#the_pygmalion_effect_and_the_golem_effect">the Golem effect</link>) and act accordingly.
</para>

<para>
Thank someone for doing something you like. But be honest and tell someone
if you dislike some action he took, or one of their works/creations (even
if you feel they are your superior).
</para>

<para>
Express interest in the other person. Ask them "What's up?", "What's new?",
etc. If he says "nothing much" tell them <link
xlink:href="https://twitter.com/shlomif/status/635904227890458624">they should
try to be less boring than that</link>.
</para>

<para>
I recall that during <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2018_FIFA_World_Cup_Final">the 2018
FIFA World Cup Final</link>, the <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kolinda_Grabar-Kitarovi%C4%87">Croatian
president</link>, who is a woman, was so sweet and hugged all the (male)
players of both teams: her native country, Croatia — and France — which won the
match.
</para>

<para>
Similarly, <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_II">Queen
Elizabeth II</link> has reportedly recently <link
xlink:href="https://www.manchestereveningnews.co.uk/news/greater-manchester-news/guest-honour-queen-leaves-couple-685253">actually
attended</link> a wedding to which a British couple invited her as a
joke.<footnote label="comedy-is-serious" xml:id="comedy_serious"><para>To quote <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Peter_Ustinov">Peter Ustinov</link>:
<quote>Comedy is simply a funny way of being serious</quote>.</para></footnote>
</para>

<para>
Sometimes people may refuse to interact with you, in that case say: “OK, no
problem, have a nice day!”.
</para>

<para>
It is also a good idea to compliment your friends and acquaintances, of
whatever sex, for their looks. I recall telling a gorgeous young woman who
came to visit one of the fellow patients in the hospital: “You are
beautiful”, and she thanked me for that, and noted that nobody had told her
that in several years. (Which made me sad.)
</para>

<section xml:id="dont-be-afraid-to-ask-for-help">

<info>
<title>Don’t be afraid to ask for help</title>
</info>

<para>
One important thing to note is that we all have our limitations and we
are not good at everything. As a result, it is important that we sometimes
ask other people for help, despite whatever <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feudalism">Feudalism</link>-like take
on “independence” there
may be. For example, I prefer not to cook complex meals myself, because cooking
and learning to cook would be a grand <link xlink:href="#time-is-much-more-important-than-money">waste of time</link> for me and I'd produce mediocre at best
results.
</para>

<para>
For some additional inspiration, you may wish to listen to the Beatles' songs
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Help!_(song)">"Help!"</link>
and <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/With_a_Little_Help_from_My_Friends">"With
a Little Help from My Friends"</link>.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="pick-up-art">

<info>
<title>Thoughts about how to Approach a MOTAS</title>
</info>

<para>
"Be excellent to each other" and being honest has implications with
respect to how a man or a woman should approach a member of the
appropriate sexes (or <link
xlink:href="http://www.catb.org/jargon/html/M/MOTAS.html">MOTAS</link>).
If you are interested in testing the waters for a long-term
relationship, then a good strategy will be to simply say: <quote>Hi, I
like you and think you are
beautiful/handsome/cute/hot/sexy/gorgeous/etc. What do you say we go on
a date?</quote> Either he or she will agree, or you have wasted much
less time.
</para>

<para>
Note that girls should feel free to approach guys this way too.  In my
<link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/stories/">stories</link>,
I have tried to encourage women to become more sexually assertive, but
it seems that most Israeli girls did not get the memo, and are still
shy and playing it hard to get.  <footnote label="israeli-popularity" xml:id="shlomifish_org_in_israel"><para>It is possible my site
has not been as popular in Israel as it could be, because it is written
almost entirely in English, and because I have not been too active on
social media that is popular in Israel such as Facebook, Instagram, and
WhatsApp.  </para></footnote>
</para>

<para>
What if you are interested in a one-off sexual intercourse? Nothing
wrong with that. You can learn about how to do it from Jazz (=
the name of one of the characters)
from the show
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Fresh_Prince_of_Bel-Air">The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air</link>.
As he said in a <link
xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KcD7hvH0Wk8">an excerpt from an episode</link>:
<quote>let's go get
some barbecue and get busy</quote>. Or as DAILY GRADVICE put it for a
girl trying to seduce a guy: <link
xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=21uXcvD5lPs"><quote>I want you to
sail your dick ship into my lady port.</quote></link>.
</para>

<para>
Naturally, it doesn't have to be these exact words, but the point
stands: be honest, sincere, and candid, cut to the chase and don't play
games.
</para>

</section>

</section>

<section xml:id="strategy-for-winning">

<info>
<title>Strategy for Winning</title>
</info>

<para>
I think the following strategy is useful for succeeding in life:
</para>

<orderedlist>

<listitem>
<para>
Admit that you want to become more <link xlink:href="#meaning-of-able-competent">able
and competent</link>.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>

<para>
However, note that you won't mind "losing", if it means avoiding hurting
yourself or others, or even avoiding remaining miserable or unhappy for too long.
( <link xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7hx4gdlfamo">"You gotta
know when to walk away."</link> )
</para>

<para>
<quote xlink:href="#being_considered_a_sucker">It is better to be considered a "sucker" (= generous) than to
acquire an enemy.</quote>
</para>

</listitem>

<listitem>

<para>
I may have competitors, but not only will I not try to immorally
hinder them, but will encourage them, and try to publicly share my knowledge,
thoughts, and opinions with them (given the time frame), and even
recommend them to my customers or fans.
</para>

</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
The important thing is to have fun ( <link xlink:href="#amateurs">geeks / "amateurs"</link> ),
identify with the cause, and have a well-rounded life. Perhaps even prolong
the 'fight'.
</para>
</listitem>

</orderedlist>

<para>
Also see <link xlink:href="#benevolent-psychological-warfare">the Golden Rule</link>.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="YouTube">

<info>
<title>YouTube</title>
</info>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/">YouTube</link> is a video
sharing site which you've probably heard of. While there are many
official videos by signed artists or by the film owners' copyrights,
there is also a huge ecosystem of original "direct-to-YouTube" art
created by the so called "YouTubers". They upload anything from bootleg
videos of songs, to technical tutorials, to low cost covers (often just
a man or a woman singing and playing a guitar, a piano or even an electric
organ or A cappella), to parodies, to lyric videos, to live recordings
of any musicians or comedians.
</para>

<para>
Now, some people still look down on YouTubers thinking that covers can never
be better than the original, but having been introduced to the world of
YouTube covers, I can often prove them wrong:
</para>

<orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n6KAGqjdmsk">Tiffany Alvord’s cover
of Hurt Me Tomorrow by K'NAAN</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d2RZXeQc5HU">Jess Greenberg’s
cover of "Highway to Hell" by AC/DC</link> (somewhat NSFW - "boobs")
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n5HexLIqWY8">Alex Boye and
Mom Bloggers United Africanised Cover of Katy Perry’s Roar</link>
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/Files/files/video/Me%20Singing%20%22I%20Will%20Always%20Love%20You%22%20by%20Whitney%20Houston-CBdmpvPa73g.mp4">Christina Grimmie's (RIP)
karaoke cover of Whitney Houston (also RIP)’s "I Will Always Love You"</link>
</para>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>

<para>
Naturally, there is a lot of junk on YouTube - <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sturgeon's_law">Sturgeon's law
("ninety percent of anything is crap")</link> is still true, and that may
include <link
xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc6rd10fdTTa8IBAdau_Cww">my own
YouTube channel</link>.
</para>

<para>
One problem with YouTube is that many videos have been removed, or
censored, or
disappeared, or blocked in certain regions (often by automated
filters). Some people like me try to use
<link xlink:href="https://youtube-dl.org/">youtube-dl</link>
or similar downloaders to download every video that we like from
YouTube, and while some die hard copyright puritans have looked
down on that, I still support that as a way to battle censorship.

<footnote label="Google vs. youtube-dl" xml:id="youtube-dl-DMCA">
<para>
Someone told me in a chat, that he believed that Google (who owns
YouTube) will do a DMCA takedown for GitHub to censor youtube-dl,
but even if they were stupid enough to do that (which I doubt), it
likely would not completely stop youtube-dl, whose open source public
domain source code has thousands of git clones and forks.
</para>
</footnote>

</para>

<para>
While I do not condone the <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YouTube_headquarters_shooting">recent
YouTube shooting</link> (by a woman no less), I believe that YouTube has
brought it upon themselves by the aggressive and irrational content
filtering and removal, that many YouTube creators and users have been
witnessing.
</para>

<para xml:id="emulate-YouTubers">
I believe that signed artists and creators (or the somewhat more professional
ones) should <emphasis role="bold">emulate YouTubers</emphasis> and start indie
channels where they post regular collaborations with other YouTubers: from the
better known to the relatively obscure.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="amateur-modelled-commerce">

<info>
<title>Amateur-modelled commerce</title>
</info>

<para>
Capitalism has been getting a bad reputation since Karl Marx published
his book <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Das_Kapital">Das Kapital</link>
or as Neo-Tech put it:
</para>

<blockquote>

<para>
The dictionary definition of capitalism is: An economic system characterized by
private ownership of capital goods and by investments that are determined by
private decision rather than by state control. Prices, production and
distribution of goods are determined by a free market.
</para>

<para>
…
</para>

<para>
But most writers and commentators put dishonest altruistic-platonistic
connotations on the meaning of capitalism: A system of exploitation of the weak
by the strong -- devoid of love and good will. A system in which unwanted goods
and services are pushed onto consumers through clever, deceptive advertising
for the sole purpose of profits and greed. Capitalism dominates most Western
governments. Capitalism, big business, and fascism are synonymous.
</para>

</blockquote>

<para>
I am no longer a <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Libertarianism">libertarianism</link> purist, but I still think Capitalism and
liberalism are the best economic system and political system respectively.
</para>

<para>
That put aside, here are some thoughts about a more <link xlink:href="#amateurs">amateur / geeky</link> take on commerce that we can consider:
</para>

<orderedlist>

<listitem>

<para>
I once attended an Israeli <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LiveJournal">LiveJournal</link>-ers
meetup (back when LiveJournal was more popular outside Russia) which took place
in a vegetarian Indian-food restaurant in central Tel Aviv. That restaurant
allowed one to eat as much as they want from the buffet and pay as much (or as
little) as they want.
</para>

<para>
Now, I ate some of the food there which was pretty good, and decided to pay 70
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Israeli_new_shekel">ILS</link>.
This is whereas I recall that, at the time, a hamburger meal at a decent restaurant
costed between 40 ILS and 50 ILS. Why did I pay so much? Because I appreciated
their trust and felt generous.
</para>

</listitem>

<listitem>

<para>
Creators of digital media (or "content") may opt to initially release their
works under relatively restrictive licences such as <link
xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">Creative
Commons CC-by-nc-sa</link> or <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affero_General_Public_License">the
Affero GPL</link>, and sell commercial or proprietary exceptions to the
licence.  Alternatively, they can ask for money to relicense the works
under less
restrictive licences such as <link
xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">CC-by</link>, <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MIT_License">the MIT licence</link>,
or even <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creative_Commons_license#Zero_/_public_domain">CC0
/ public domain</link>. For everybody and their benefit.
</para>

</listitem>

<listitem xml:id="being_considered_a_sucker">

<para>
I have been doing software development commissions where I give a rough
estimate of the time it will take me <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=shlomif-multiply-by-pi">by multiplying my original estimate by 3</link>
and charge 50 USD / hour (which is a good rate in Israel) and I do not
charge if the customer is unhappy with my deliverables. This is because
I'd rather be considered
a <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/computers/open-source/gpl-bsd-and-suckerism/">"sucker"</link>
than acquire a new enemy.
</para>

<para>
Note that the deliverables of a recent commission were <link xlink:href="https://github.com/shlomif/dosbox/commit/50a6334e3713d8647553aa8d1809c0243633cb60">made open source</link>
by permission of the customer, because although he paid me to work on
some change he needed, he was also happy to share it with the world at
large.
</para>

</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
Some people online lamented the fact that some <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammy_Award">Grammy Award</link>-winning artists had to use
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patreon">Patreon</link> (or
similar) donation pledges to sponsor their albums, but it is quite similar
to most philosophers of ancient times, who were entertainers who collected
donations from the attendees after their performances.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
Counterintuitively, charging more <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=joel-camels-rubber-duckies-11">may
yield a bigger demand:</link>
</para>

<blockquote>

<para>
And, in fact, you can’t even be sure that the demand
curve is downward sloping.
</para>

<para>
The only reason we assumed that the demand curve is
downward sloping is that we assumed things like “if
Freddy is willing to buy a pair of sneakers for $130,
he is certainly willing to buy those same sneakers for
$20.” Right? Ha! Not if Freddy is an American teenager!
American teenagers would not be caught dead in $20
sneakers. It’s, like, um, the death penalty? if you are
wearing sneakers?  that only cost $20 a pair? in
school?
</para>

<para>
I’m not joking around here: prices send signals. Movies
in my town cost, I think, $11. Criminy. There used to
be a movie theatre that had movies for $3.  Did anyone
go there? I DON’T THINK SO. It’s obviously just a
dumping ground for lousy movies. Somebody is now at the
bottom of the East River with $20.00 cement sneakers
because they dared to tell the consumer which movies
the industry thought were lousy.
</para>

</blockquote>

<para>
In addition, in the book <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Princess_Bride_(novel)">The
Princess Bride</link>, there is a story of a swords' craftsman, whose secret
better craftsman delegator was killed. He charged more and more for his now
inferior results. However, the more he charged, the greater the demand was.
</para>

</listitem>

<listitem>

<blockquote>

<para>
<emphasis role="bold">Faith:</emphasis> well, "living on the streets" is kind-of a stretch. See: I took Peter
the mafio's advice and collected money from people in exchange for stand-up
comedy/philosophy sessions and earned my keeps this way. Just for the record,
being original is <link xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5kQCpsPnnew">a Big Mistake</link>; I crossoverred stuff all over the place.
</para>

</blockquote>

<para>
( Quote from <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/Buffy/A-Few-Good-Slayers/">my “Buffy - a Few Good Slayers” screenplay</link> . )
</para>

</listitem>

</orderedlist>

<para>
For more insights, see:
</para>

<orderedlist>

<listitem>
<para>

<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/computers/web/models-for-commerce/">“Alternative” models for web commerce</link> - on my site.

</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>

<link xlink:href="https://github.com/nayafia/lemonade-stand">nayafia's “lemonade-stand”: A handy guide to financial support for open source</link>

</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>

<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/joel-on-software.html#joel-camels-rubber-duckies-1">Quotes from Joel on Software’s essay about The Pricing of Software (or other goods)</link>

</para>
</listitem>

</orderedlist>

</section>

<section xml:id="amateurs-in-sports">

<info>
<title>Amateurs in Sports</title>
</info>

<para>
Before the industrialisation of the Far East,
and the way the West interpreted martial arts, with the coloured belts and
all, there were regional masters of these arts, who practised them as much as
they could and honed their skills. However, despite all that, they never ruled
out that they would one day fight against someone who never faught before,
and lose.
</para>

<para>
In <link xlink:href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Three_Musketeers">The
Three Musketeers</link>, Dumas tells the story of how d’Artagnan who is a young
swordsman without much of an official training, from a remote region of France,
eventually becomes the best fighter in France. This is despite the fact that
his peers, Athos, Porthos, and Aramis, have much more experience and training.
</para>

<para>
The short-lived sitcom
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phenom_(TV_series)">Phenom</link>
depicted a young skillful Tennis player whose happiness was ruined due to
living in boarding school conditions. Even if she practised more, she lost
the psychological war.
</para>

<para>
Building on <link xlink:href="#strategy-for-winning">the strategy for winning</link>
and <link xlink:href="#amateurs">the "amateur/geekdom" ethos</link> we can see that in ~2022, most good
paid sportsmen are increasingly enjoying their work, and don't mind losing too much.
</para>

<orderedlist>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2018_FIFA_World_Cup_Final">Croatia were the runnerups of the 2018 FIFA world cup</link>, despite being a small country.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.newsweek.com/scripps-national-spelling-bee-winners-1440603">8 First Place Winners in a USA National spelling bee</link>
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
Michael Phelps record/
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.essentiallysports.com/atp-tennis-news-jannik-sinner-defeats-vasek-pospisil-to-create-history-in-open-era-tennis/">“[ The then-19-years old ] Jannik Sinner Defeats Vasek Pospisil to Create History in Open Era Tennis - EssentiallySports”</link>
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/sport/football/article-4389760/USA-women-s-team-suffer-5-2-loss-FC-Dallas-U-15-boys.html">USA women's team suffer 5-2 loss to FC Dallas' U-15 boys</link>
</para>
</listitem>

</orderedlist>

</section>

<section xml:id="Christina_Grimmie">

<info>
<title>Christina Grimmie (1994 - 2016; rest-in-peace, but likely peacefully / "complete-ly" / "shalom"-fully alive)</title>
</info>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christina_Grimmie">Wikipedia</link>
and <link xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUudDyi0JiVmSxarvU98YYQ">YouTube channel</link>.
and <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/art/recommendations/music/online-artists/fan-pages/chris-grimmie/">shlomifish.org’s Fan page</link>.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="mountain-and-muhammad">

<info>
<title>If the mountain won't come to Muhammad, then Muhammad must go to the mountain</title>
</info>

<para>
Fill in.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="people-can-change">

<info>
<title>People Can Change; Companies and countries and communities too</title>
</info>

<para>
It may surprise you, but people can change. Towards <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/Selina-Mandrake/ongoing-text.html#from-dispeller-to-selina">the
end</link> of my screenplay <emphasis>Selina Mandrake - The Slayer</emphasis>
I describe such changes among traditionally stubborn men and societies:
</para>

<orderedlist>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://memory-alpha.fandom.com/wiki/Q">Q</link>, who
had been revealed to be a humanoid, decided to appear less blasé and
show some compassion for fellow organisms, including his ex-wives
and children.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link
xlink:href="https://memory-alpha.fandom.com/wiki/Kahless_the_Unforgettable">Kahless</link>
returns on The Day of The Living Dead to guide the <link
xlink:href="https://memory-alpha.fandom.com/wiki/Klingon">Klingons</link> back
into rationality and carefulness instead of what became their traditional
stubbornness and haste.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
We admit to ourselves that sometimes
<link xlink:href="#amateurs">amateurs</link>
(being people
who like what they do, people who don’t play by the rules, and finally people
who are not professional) can compete with the large budgets and high
discipline of professionals, and even exceed it, because they can deliver more
and at greater capacity, tend to think outside the box, and simply tend to
avoid the many invisible rules that plague more professional structures.
</para>
</listitem>

</orderedlist>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linus_Torvalds">Linus Torvalds</link> surprised quite a few people by <link
xlink:href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-45664640">admitting that being
needlessly rude was detrimental to the growth of the Linux kernel’s development
community</link> rather than something that he believed was good for it. There
were some conspiracy hypotheses about how exactly he came to that realisation,
but it is not unthinkable for a person to change their mind.
</para>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Stallman">Richard
Stallman</link> also decided to resign from his long term role as president of
the
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_Software_Foundation">Free
Software Foundation</link>, which also was a surprise to many. The exact
impetus for that decision is irrelevant, and Dr. Stallman is planning to remain
active. Furthermore, the new president will likely be better and more effective
than him.
</para>

<para>
Companies can change too. Under its new leadership, <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft">Microsoft</link> has open
sourced many projects, or developed them as open source to begin with. It also
<link
xlink:href="https://news.microsoft.com/2018/06/04/microsoft-to-acquire-github-for-7-5-billion/">acquired
GitHub</link>, and despite some predictions of doom and gloom from <link
xlink:href="#fear-is-path-to-dark-side">paranoid</link> users, it seems that
the user experience (= "UX") of GitHub has improved since the acquisition.
</para>

<para>
Naturally, there are some paranoid conspiracy hypotheses about evil Microsoft
intentions to secretly take over and dominate the open source world. I, on the
other hand, try <link xlink:href="#hakuna-matata">to avoid worrying ("Hakuna
Matata")</link> about such farfetched scenarios before they have materialised.
I still recall some clueless users of Microsoft software saying that "Microsoft
will buy Linux!" in the mid-to-late 1990s, and that naturally didn't happen
because of the <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_open-source_software">FOSS</link>
nature of the licences (whether <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyleft">copyleft</link> or <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Permissive_software_licence">permissive</link>),
and the superior <link xlink:href="#amateurs">amateur</link>-based model of
development.
<footnote label="Embrace, extend, and extinguish" xml:id="embrace_extend">
<para>
I believe these include fears of the
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Embrace,_extend,_and_extinguish">"Embrace, extend, and extinguish" strategy</link>,
which has also been unintentionally practised by many open-source projects,
can usually be overcome using reverse engineering, and seems to have been falling
out of favour by Microsoft anyway.
</para>
</footnote>
</para>

<para>
As the Chuck Norris factoid I came up with <link
xlink:href="https://twitter.com/shlomif/status/1175452478273478656">goes</link>:
<quote>Chuck Norris' round house kicks are licensed under the public domain
because no one else can successfully emulate them.</quote>
</para>
</section>

<section xml:id="four-kinds-of-fools">

<info>
<title>Six kinds of fools: avoiding prejudice</title>
</info>

<blockquote>
<blockquote>
<para>There are two kinds of fools. One says, “This is old, and therefore good”.
And one says, “This is new, and therefore better”.</para>
</blockquote>
<para>
  —
  <link xlink:href="http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/John_Brunner">John
  Brunner</link>, <emphasis>The Shockwave Rider</emphasis>
</para>
<blockquote>
<para>Two more kinds of fools. One says: “This is popular, and therefore good”.
The other says: “This is good because it’s not popular”.</para>
</blockquote>
<para>
  — Shlomi Fish (though may not be a 100% original sentiment).
</para>
<para>
(And recently people had prejudice against "mainstream" culture.)
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
It is important not to be prejudiced against things just because they are
old, new, popular, unpopular, <link xlink:href="https://twitter.com/shlomif/status/1165982522091737088">seem like "a religion"</link>,
were hyped, seem blasphemous or cringeworthy, are politically incorrect,
etc.
</para>

<para>
I've been criticised for still using <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML">XML</link> and
related technologies, because they seem to have fallen out of favour.
But I have good reasons for using XML and use it for different use cases
than <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSON">JSON</link>
and <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YAML">YAML</link>
and various <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightweight_markup_language">lightweight
markup languages</link>, which I also use and like for different purposes.
</para>

<para>
Similarly, back when <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friends">the Friends TV show</link>
was airing, some hard core computer geeks dismissed it, due to it being too mainstream,
while I found it very good.
<footnote label="friends-fan-fic" xml:id="friends_fan_fic">
<para>
I also wrote a <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/TOneW-the-Fountainhead/">Friends’ fan fic
episode</link> that parodies the book <emphasis>The Fountainhead</emphasis> by
Ayn Rand.
</para>
</footnote>
</para>

<para>
Lately, some people have looked down on adult male fans of the show <link
xlink:href="https://mlp.fandom.com/wiki/My_Little_Pony_Friendship_is_Magic"><emphasis>My
Little Pony: Friendship is Magic</emphasis></link> because it was originally
intended for young children, especially young girls. This is even though most
male adult fans (including me) are heterosexual and that they include some
combat soldiers. In <link
xlink:href="https://twitter.com/shlomif/status/1174358484726497280">a
tweet</link>, I wrote:
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
I've always considered myself a little "girly" and now I'm even kinda proud of
it, and am an otherwise straight male. “You can never truly appreciate Gilmore
Girls until you've watched it in the original Klingon!”
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
I think you'd be surprised at how much
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/philosophy/putting-all-cards-on-the-table-2013/#best_warriors">unmacho
and geeky some of the best male warriors are</link>.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="encouraging-and-handling-criticism">
<info>
<title>Criticism</title>
</info>

<para>
I feel that one should <link xlink:href="http://shlomifishswiki.branchable.com/Encourage_criticism_and_try_to_get_offended/">Encourage people to criticise them</link> and try to get offended,
because negative criticism highlights things where one can improve,
including various falsehoods that one believes in, but
are in fact false. (See: <link xlink:href="https://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/george_bernard_shaw_101824">"All great
truths begin as blasphemies"</link>).
On the other hand, if one only tries to hear flattery or yesmen, they are likely to get trapped in
an echo chamber, and become surrounded by <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sycophancy">sycophants</link>,
and improve too little.
</para>

<para>
On the other hand, one should
<link xlink:href="http://shlomifishswiki.branchable.com/Never_Try_to_Please_Everyone/">never try to please everyone</link>
because some people will always dislike some aspects of your work, and the best
thing you can do is disagree and move on. Back when I referred a certain fellow
open source developer (who
is a Christian American) to my <link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/Star-Trek/We-the-Living-Dead/">Star
Trek: “We, the Living Dead”</link> fan fic
he objected to the use of the phrase <quote>hot girls</quote> there, and
claimed I should delete the offending pages from my site. However, I refused
because I didn't disapprove of using that phrase there, and even if I did, I'd
rather not remove such offending material completely, but rather either revise
it or add a disclaimer note.
</para>

<section xml:id="bikeshed_colour">

<info>
<title>Colour of the Bikeshed</title>
</info>

<para>
A somewhat more involved case of criticism is <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Color_of_the_bikeshed">Parkinson’s Law of Triviality</link>
or the “colour of the bikeshed” argument
in which discussions about trivial matters which many people can understand are given
disproportionate time. In this case, it is important to sometimes avoid insisting on
one's preference. Recently, the local Israeli <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_open-source_software">Free and open-source software</link> community
contemplated whether to use <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordPress">WordPress</link>
or a <link xlink:href="https://davidwalsh.name/introduction-static-site-generators">static site generator</link>
for the new linux.org.il site and when the consensus settled on WordPress, I accepted
that despite the fact that I preferred the other option. That is because wasting time
on such trivialities will not be fruitful.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="kipling_if">

<info>
<title>Quote from "If—" by Rudyard Kipling</title>
</info>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/If%E2%80%94">"If—" by Rudyard Kipling</link> is
a famous poem which is the favourite of mine and many past and present people (including
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ayn_Rand">Ayn Rand</link>). Quoting from it:
</para>

<blockquote>

<para>
If you can keep your head when all about you
</para>

<para>
Are losing theirs and blaming it on you,
</para>

<para>
If you can trust yourself when all men doubt you,
</para>

<para>
But make allowance for their doubting too;
</para>

<para>
If you can wait and not be tired by waiting,
</para>

<para>
Or being lied about, don’t deal in lies,
</para>

<para>
Or being hated, don’t give way to hating,
</para>

<para>
And yet don’t look too good, nor talk too wise:
</para>

</blockquote>
</section>

</section>

<section xml:id="dont-be-afraid-to-live">

<info>
<title>Do not be afraid to live</title>
</info>

<para>
The film
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Quick_and_the_Dead_(1995_film)">The Quick and the Dead (from 1995)</link>, which I watched at home, provided some inspiration about why being “afraid to live” is often detrimental. Some people are afraid to voice opinions online. I was also told I should not approach strangers on the street, even though that they are extremely unlikely to be harmful.
</para>

<para>
I was also
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/meta/FAQ/#revealing_incriminating_details">told I should not share incriminating details</link>
about me and my past online, like the facts that I've been exempt from
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Israel_Defense_Forces">Israeli military (= IDF)</link> service, or that I've used to suffer from clinical depressions and hypo-manias.
</para>

<para>
If human resources (HR) personell, try to find faults in your online presence, they likely
will always be unhappy. (Also see <link xlink:href="#the_pygmalion_effect_and_the_golem_effect">Golem effect</link> and <link xlink:href="#four-kinds-of-fools">Prejudice</link>).) I prefer to work only for employers who appreciate honesty, sincerity, and openness.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="forgiveness">

<info>
<title>Forgiveness</title>
</info>

<para>
<link xlink:href="#do_and_let_do__live_and_let_live">Saladin</link> forgave the Knights Templar for their vandalism and murder,
and let them go on their way as reformed and
happy and sane individuals, despite their past criminal track
record. Given that, you
can forgive someone who has offended you or
<link xlink:href="#sexiness-as-competence">insulted someone
you care about.</link>
</para>

<para>
Lao Tsu noted in <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tao_Te_Ching">Tao Te
Ching</link> that <quote>Those kind, be kind to them; Those unkind, be
kind to them also.</quote> and there is also the aphorism
<quote>keep your friends close and enemies closer.</quote>
from <link xlink:href="https://www.quora.com/Who-said-Keep-your-friends-close-and-your-enemies-closer">the Godfather part II</link>.
Finally, there is the old adage that <quote>To err
is human. To forgive — divine</quote>.
</para>

<para>
Your <link xlink:href="#time-is-much-more-important-than-money">time</link>
is likely too precious to hold grudges against your friends, your past
friends, or even people who currently dislike you.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="managing-your-memory">

<info>
<title>Managing Your Memory</title>
</info>

<para>
As I wrote in <link xlink:href="http://unarmed.shlomifish.org/1991.html">“Sherlock Holmes
about the Awk programming language”</link>:
</para>

<blockquote>

<para>
I enjoyed reading some of Sir Arthur Conan Doyle’s writings about the
fictional detective
<link xlink:href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sherlock_Holmes">Sherlock
Holmes</link> when I was younger, which were entertaining (although
possibly distanced from the way actual crime investigation actually
works), and interesting. I vividly recall one excerpt from the very
first Sherlock Holmes story,
<link xlink:href="http://en.wikisource.org/wiki/A_Study_in_Scarlet">A
Study in Scarlet</link>:
</para>
<blockquote>
<para>
His ignorance was as remarkable as his knowledge. Of contemporary
literature, philosophy and politics he appeared to know next to
nothing. Upon my quoting Thomas Carlyle, he enquired in the naivest
way who he might be and what he had done. My surprise reached a
climax, however, when I found incidentally that he was ignorant of
the Copernican Theory and of the composition of the Solar System.
That any civilized human being in this nineteenth century should not
be aware that the earth travelled round the sun appeared to be to me
such an extraordinary fact that I could hardly realize it.
</para>
<para>
&quot;You appear to be astonished,&quot; he said, smiling at my
expression of surprise. &quot;Now that I do know it I shall do my
best to forget it.&quot;
</para>
<para>
&quot;To forget it!&quot;
</para>
<para>
&quot;You see,&quot; he explained, &quot;I consider that a man's
brain originally is like a little empty attic, and you have to stock
it with such furniture as you choose. A fool takes in all the lumber
of every sort that he comes across, so that the knowledge which
might be useful to him gets crowded out, or at best is jumbled up
with a lot of other things, so that he has a difficulty in laying
his hands upon it. Now the skilful workman is very careful indeed as
to what he takes into his brain attic. He will have nothing but the
tools which may help him in doing his work, but of these he has a
large assortment, and all in the most perfect order. It is a mistake
to think that that little room has elastic walls and can distend to
any extent. Depend upon it there comes a time when for every
addition of knowledge you forget something that you knew before. It
is of the highest importance, therefore, not to have useless facts
elbowing out the useful ones.&quot;
</para>
<para>
&quot;But the Solar System!&quot; I protested.
</para>
<para>
&quot;What the deuce is it to me?&quot; he interrupted impatiently;
&quot;you say that we go round the sun. If we went round the moon it
would not make a pennyworth of difference to me or to my work.&quot;
</para>
</blockquote>
<para>
(<link xlink:href="http://en.wikisource.org/wiki/A_Study_in_Scarlet/Part_1/Chapter_2">Chapter
2 of A Study in Scarlet</link> by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, under the
public domain in most countries.)
</para>
<para>
Conan Doyle was naturally exaggerating here in portraying the ideal of
Sherlock Holmes (as few, if any, human beings can forget that the
Earth revolves around the Sun), but the principle still stands: we
need to make a conscious decision of how to manage our memory, because
there is a limit to how many different aspects can put inside our
resident memory, or otherwise we'll forget more important stuff.
</para>
<para>
So what does it has to do with the Awk programming language? Many
decades after A Study in Scarlet,
<link xlink:href="http://www.catb.org/esr/">Eric S. Raymond</link> had
this to say in his book
<link xlink:href="http://www.catb.org/esr/writings/taoup/"><emphasis>The
Art of Unix Programming</emphasis></link>:
</para>
<blockquote>
<para>
A case study of awk is included to point out that it is not a model
for emulation; in fact, since 1990 it has largely fallen out of use.
It has been superseded by new-school scripting languages—notably
Perl, which was explicitly designed to be an awk killer. The reasons
are worthy of examination, because they constitute a bit of a
cautionary tale for minilanguage designers.
</para>
<para>
The awk language was originally designed to be a small, expressive
special-purpose language for report generation. Unfortunately, it
turns out to have been designed at a bad spot on the
complexity-vs.-power curve. The action language is noncompact, but
the pattern-driven framework it sits inside keeps it from being
generally applicable — that's the worst of both worlds. And the
new-school scripting languages can do anything awk can; their
equivalent programs are usually just as readable, if not more so.
</para>
<para>
For a few years after the release of Perl in 1987, awk remained
competitive simply because it had a smaller, faster implementation.
But as the cost of compute cycles and memory dropped, the economic
reasons for favoring a special-purpose language that was relatively
thrifty with both lost their force. Programmers increasingly chose
to do awklike things with Perl or (later) Python, rather than
<emphasis role="strong">keep two different scripting languages in
their heads</emphasis>.[90] By the year 2000 awk had become little
more than a memory for most old-school Unix hackers, and not a
particularly nostalgic one.
</para>
<para>
Falling costs have changed the tradeoffs in minilanguage design.
Restricting your design's capabilities to buy compactness may still
be a good idea, but doing so to economize on machine resources is a
bad one. Machine resources get cheaper over time, but
<emphasis role="strong">space in programmers' heads only gets more
expensive</emphasis>. Modern minilanguages can either be general but
noncompact, or specialized but very compact; specialized but
noncompact simply won't compete.
</para>
</blockquote>
<para>
(Emphasis mine.)
</para>
<para>
(<link xlink:href="http://www.catb.org/esr/writings/taoup/html/ch08s02.html#awk">Case
Study: awk in minilanguages</link> in <emphasis>The Art of Unix
Programming</emphasis> by Eric Steven Raymond, text available under
the Creative Commons Attribution-NonDerivatives licence, and hopefully
quoted here (with attribution) under
<link xlink:href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fair_use">fair
use</link> auspices.)
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
I still keep awk out of my resident memory, but there are many other
things I do not remember nor care enough to. For example, I do not remember
the names of the current Israeli president or that of the current <link
xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chief_of_the_General_Staff_(Israel)">Israeli
Chief of the General Staff</link>. I am almost sure they are
both great people, but remembering their names is pointless for me.
</para>

<para>
We have to manage our memory with care, or we'll forget stuff that is
much more important.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="selling-for-stupider-ppl">

<info>
<title>Selling for people stupider than you</title>
</info>

<para>
I suggest you sell / develop products for people as smart as you.
If you target stupid people, then:
</para>

<orderedlist>

<listitem>
<para>
You <link xlink:href="https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2001/05/05/what-is-the-work-of-dogs-in-this-country/">won't eat your own dog food</link>.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
You will
<link xlink:href="#the_pygmalion_effect_and_the_golem_effect">practise the Golem effect</link>
(= expecting a person to worsen, and they indeed become worse).
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
You will
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/culture/case-for-commercial-fan-fiction/indiv-nodes/hacking_and_amateur__vs__conformism_and_professional.xhtml">target an increasingly marginal demographic given smart geeky hackers are mainstream, attractive, "cool kids"</link>.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
Stupid people can likely afford to pay less, and will require more
hand-holding.
</para>
</listitem>

</orderedlist>

<blockquote>
<para>
The word "idiot-proof" [= laymen-proof],
after bundled with <link
xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=joel-remarkable-customer-service-3">Joel
Spolsky's advice</link> to permanently fix users-reported-problems,
gets a new meaning when some laymen are tech geeks who
have GitHub accounts and are versed in the command-line, e.g:
<link xlink:href="https://github.com/shlomif/fortune-mod/issues/45">fortune-mod issue #45</link>
 . I may be a "victim" of my own success.
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
Also see:
</para>

<orderedlist>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Road#A_metaphorical_%22Royal_Road%22_in_famous_quotations">"There is no Royal Road to geometry"</link>
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/computers/web/choice-of-docs-formats/#word-processors">A note about word processors</link>
</para>
<blockquote>
<para>
As I noted in a Reddit comment, word processors are the kind of programs that
are created by smart people for people who are less smart than them, because
smart programmers can use text editors and markup languages.
</para>
</blockquote>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
Paul Graham about Java:
</para>

<orderedlist>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="http://www.paulgraham.com/javacover.html">"Java's Cover"</link>
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="http://www.paulgraham.com/trevrejavcov.html">Trevor re "Java's Cover"</link>
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
Any technology that has the outward features of Java (hype, accessibility,
committee design, ulterior commercial motives, ...) is probably designed for
drones, so avoid it for the same reason you would avoid a novel with Fabio on
the cover, or an inn that advertises parking for trucks. They may be right for
their target audience. They may be created by smart people. They're just not
meant for you.
</para>
</blockquote>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="http://www.paulgraham.com/vanlfsp.html">"LFM vs. LFSP"</link>
</para>
</listitem>

</orderedlist>

<para>
( Note that modern Java may have some legitimate use-cases despite having had
growing pains like these. )
</para>

</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/fortunes/show.cgi?id=chromatic-about-testing-DSLs">chromatic about testing domain-specific languages (“DSLs”):</link>
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
Our clients are the parents, guardians, and teachers of children between the ages of eight and twelve inclusive.
</para>

<para>
The intent of Cucumber is to make readable testcases, just as the intent of <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/COBOL">COBOL</link> and <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AppleScript">AppleScript</link> and <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visual_programming_language">visual component programming</link> is to enable non-programmers to create software without having to learn how to program.
</para>
</blockquote>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/meta/FAQ/#how_site_is_generated">Smart software developers can often use static site generators</link> - instead of server-side CMSes such as WordPress or Drupal.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<para>
<link xlink:href="http://www.amatecon.com/fish.html">“Give a man a fish; you have fed him for today. Teach a man to fish; and you have fed him for a lifetime”</link> -
I invest time in learning useful technologies, and have little patience
for people who wish to remain ignorant of knowledge which I consider
essential.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
<blockquote>
<para>
I expect every cultured person to learn <link xlink:href="https://duckduckgo.com/?q=xhtml5&amp;atb=v140-1&amp;ia=web">XHTML5</link> and <link xlink:href="https://github.com/shlomif/Freenode-programming-channel-FAQ/blob/master/FAQ_with_ToC__generated.md#i-want-to-learn-programming-which-language-should-i-start-with">Python</link> and English. Learning
Latin, <link xlink:href="https://github.com/shlomif/Freenode-programming-channel-FAQ/blob/master/FAQ_with_ToC__generated.md#how-are-c-c-and-c-c-sharp-related-how-are-they-different">C/C++</link>, and cooking, is optional.
</para>
</blockquote>

<para>
( <link xlink:href="https://twitter.com/shlomif/status/1618628716137185287">Tweet by @shlomif</link> )
</para>
</listitem>

</orderedlist>

</section>

<section xml:id="fanfic-and-rpf">

<info>
<title>The legitimacy of Fanfic and Real Person Fic</title>
</info>

<para>
I am an unapologetic and proud fan fiction and real person fiction (= "RPF") writer:
</para>

<orderedlist>
<listitem>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/meta/FAQ/#why_fan_fic">Q: Why do you write mostly fan-fiction and crossovers?</link>
</para>

<blockquote>

<para>
Lawrence Lessig gives many good reasons for remixing in his book
<link xlink:href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Remix_%28book%29"><emphasis role="strong">Remix:</emphasis>
Making Art and Commerce Thrive in the Hybrid Economy</link> which I
have read and enjoyed. Writing fan-fiction and crossovers, whether in
fiction or in non-fiction (see some of my crossover essays) is the
writing equivalent of what he describes being primarily done with
music and videos.
</para>

<para>
Our aversion towards fan fiction and an insistence on
&quot;originality&quot; is mostly a 20th century fad, that is slowly
(for some values of &quot;slowly&quot;) diminishing.
</para>

<para>
Anyway, the various fiction franchises and idea systems that
influenced me are a large part of me, and I cannot throw them away
when writing my own works. I don’t have a lot of control of the ideas
I come up with, but I know I must materialise them eventually.
</para>

</blockquote>

</listitem>

<listitem>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/meta/FAQ/#why_real_person_fiction">Q: What about your real person fiction?</link>
</para>

<blockquote>
<para>
I feature or reference several celebrities in my stories (whether past
or present) as a way of
<link xlink:href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Real_person_fiction">Real
person fiction</link>. According to the Wikipedia page, such fiction
is likely to be legal if it is done in mostly good taste, which I
believe and hope is the case for me.
</para>
<para>
The general consensus is that a celebrity generally allows himself or
herself to be a subject of reuse in literature, and that includes me,
Shlomi Fish.
</para>
<para>
<emphasis role="strong">Update (2 November 2019):</emphasis> I have
now written a
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/culture/my-real-person-fan-fiction/">more
comprehensive essay</link> about why writing real person fan fiction
is good.
</para>
<para>
<emphasis role="strong">Update (26 November 2019):</emphasis> I now
realise that fan fiction and especially real person fiction can be
used to help combat the flood of new characters and names that plagues
many more &quot;original&quot; stories. People generally have a rough
concept of what characters such as
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/Chuck-Norris/">Chuck
Norris</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/Emma-Watson/">Emma
Watson</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Stallman">Richard
Stallman</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moses">Moses</link>,
or <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miss_Piggy">Miss
Piggy</link>, are like and generally can better remember them because
they thought about them a lot.
</para>
</blockquote>

</listitem>

<listitem>

<para>
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/philosophy/culture/my-real-person-fan-fiction/">Why I will continue to write my real person fan fiction (fanfic)</link>
</para>

</listitem>

</orderedlist>

<para>
There has been a lot of fan fiction and real person fiction in the
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hebrew_Bible">Hebrew Bible</link> and
among ancient Greek and Roman philosophers. For example, <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plato">Plato</link>'s dialogues with his mentor, Socrates
are clearly RPF. So were some of the stories that the Israelite <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nevi%27im">nevi'im</link> (mistranslated
as "prophets") told about their
contemporary or past men and women, whether positively - or often negatively.
</para>

<para>
If we look at present time, then the Muppets and Sesame Street franchises often
invite real life guests as fictionalised versions of themselves to the show,
to interact with the muppets. Parodies are also considered fan fiction
and some parodies like <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spaceballs">Spaceballs</link>
or <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Last_Action_Hero">Last Action Hero</link> (which also sports some real person fiction) are among my favourite films.
</para>

<para>
Moreover, fan fiction and especially real person fiction can be used to help
combat the problem of the flood of new names and characters that plagues
many stories that are more "original".  People generally have a rough concept of what characters such as
<link xlink:href="#Chuck_Norris">Chuck Norris</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://www.shlomifish.org/humour/bits/facts/Emma-Watson/">Emma Watson</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Stallman">Richard Stallman</link>,
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moses">Moses</link>, or
<link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miss_Piggy">Miss Piggy</link>, are
like and generally can better remember them because they thought about them
a lot.
</para>

</section>

<section xml:id="not-interrupt-foreign-speakers-when-speaking">

<info>
<title>Do not interrupt foreign speakers for every mistake</title>
</info>

<para>
A friend of mine, who is deaf from an early age, told me that he didn't learn
to verbally speak very well, because his mother interrupted him whenever he said
something wrong, which caused him to lose confidence and become demotivated.
This story has implications for speaking with people who are learning English
or a different foreign language. Try not to interrupt them on every mistake
they make, and let them speak with some errors, so they will gain confidence.
</para>

</section>

</article>
<!-- vim: set indentexpr=
-->
